Hi everybody, I'm John Kuryaku. Welcome
back to Deep Focus. I wanted to tell you
how thrilled we here have been with the
channel's success over the last couple
of months with everybody watching,
subscribing. I wanted to say thank you
very, very much. It really means a lot
to me, not just me, but my colleagues
Rebecca Miles and Chris Arnon. Uh, we're
so happy that we've had now more than
36,000 subscribers and our videos are
routinely getting tens of thousands of
views. We can't do it except with your
help. So, thank you very much. I also
wanted to thank you for the comments
that you're leaving on the videos. And I
wanted to take the opportunity to answer
some of the questions that have popped
up uh in the course of those videos.
Before we do that though, I wanted to
talk about today's latest developments
uh in the Jeffrey Epstein situation. I
say situation, it's not really a case
because Epstein's dead. He's not going
to be prosecuted. So, it's not really a
case. It is still a case for Galileain
Maxwell, however, his um alleged, not
even alleged, but his codefendant.
You might recall that Galileain Maxwell
uh was found guilty of child sex crimes
about a year ago or so and she was
sentenced to 20 years in prison.
Granted, she ended up at a minimum
security work camp for women down in
Florida. Her job at the prison has
literally been to go out to the beach
every day and pick up garbage. So, God
knows life could be a lot worse for
Galain Maxwell.
But this thing has taken on so much of a
life of its own that yesterday, Attorney
General Pam Bondi announced that Justice
Department attorneys would seek to
interview Galain Maxwell.
Why? To say what? The case is over. And
if I were Galain Maxwell, better yet, if
I were Galain Maxwell's attorney, I
would tell her to keep her mouth shut.
She's been sentenced to 20 years. That's
a long stretch. And it's not going to
get any better unless the Justice
Department decides to shorten that
stretch. They haven't proposed that.
They just said, "Oh, we're going to go
interview Gain Maxwell." No, they're
not. That's not how the justice system
works.
If Galain Maxwell's attorney is worth
his salt, and I'm sure that he is
because there's a lot of money involved
here, he's going to tell her to remain
completely silent until he can negotiate
an agreement with the Justice Department
to shave some of those years off of her
sentence and then she would be happy to
answer their questions. Right. In
addition, just a week ago,
Maxwell's attorney filed her appeal in
the Federal Circuit Court of Appeals.
Now, as a basic rule, nobody ever wins
their appeal, right? I mean, it's it's
less than 1%. And usually when people do
win among that less than 1%, it's on a
procedural issue. It's just a
technicality. It's not like courts of
appeals
read the case and say, "Oh my gosh, a
terrible mistake has been made. We're
going to overturn this conviction."
That's just that's in the movies. That
doesn't happen in real life. ProPublica
has written about this. And they have
confirmed that far fewer than 1%
of people convicted in federal courts
have won their appeals. Not only not
only has Galain Maxwell's attorney just
a week ago submitted the appeal to the
circuit court, but also a week ago the
Justice Department submitted their
response to Galileain Maxwell's appeal
in which they said, "We disagree with
literally everything that was said in
this appeal and we oppose
any easing of Glay Maxwell's sentence.
So, here we are just a week later and
the Justice Department is going to
Colleen Maxwell hand in hand and saying,
"We seem to have gotten ourselves into a
political corner here and we would
appreciate it if out of the goodness of
your heart you could rat out other
people who had something to do with
Jeffrey Epstein." That's just not how
real life works. So stay tuned to that
and don't be at all surprised if Galain
Maxwell's 20 years suddenly turned to 17
or 15 or 10 or Donald Trump with the
stroke of his pen changes it even more
radically. We're going to wait and see.
There was a second development in this
uh situation. This is a bonafide scandal
for Donald Trump. Donald Trump, despite
his more recent protestations,
campaigned on the issue of releasing all
of the information that the Justice
Department had related to the Jeffrey
Epstein uh case. Now, when he said all
information,
his supporters believed that to mean all
information, including the names of
people involved with Epstein who may
have committed sex crimes against
children.
You know from watching the news that a
week or so ago, Attorney General Pam
Bondi came out and said that after a
thorough review, it turns out there is
no so-called list of clients that
Jeffrey Epstein had uh who committed
crimes against children. Uh the list uh
doesn't exist. It may never have
existed. And sorry, but uh we're done.
Well, FBI Director Cash Patel
wanted to release more and didn't say
anything. FBI Deputy Director Dan Bonino
reportedly flipped his lid in a White
House meeting with Attorney General
Bondi and almost resigned. He actually
didn't even show up for work the next
day, a Friday. And the word was he was
going to quit because he promised people
that he would release all of the Epstein
information. And now he's being told,
"No, you can't release it." So
what is it? You know what? Let's give
the let's give the Justice Department
the benefit of the doubt and let's say,
"Okay, we believe you that there's no
list." But to to paraphrase Bill Clinton
depends on what the meaning of list is.
right now. Is there a is there a file
folder somewhere at the Justice
Department that says uh men who
committed sex crimes against children at
Jeffrey Epstein's Island? No. Okay, I I
accept that. But we also know from a
mountain of testimony by Virginia
Joffrey, God rest her soul, and other
victims of Jeffrey Epstein and his
friends
that there were recordings, there were
computer hard drives, there were
probably DVDs, and there were human
beings monitoring the recording
equipment at the island.
So why haven't those people been
deposed?
Why haven't we heard interviews with the
people who were who were apparently
taking video of men having sex with
children at the island?
Pam Bondi, God bless her. I think she
means well. I really do. I've heard from
people close to her, a lot of people
close to her, that she's a genuinely
good person who really wants to do the
right thing.
So, let's lay this out and let the
American people decide. Now, the second
the second uh event this week related to
Epstein is that Mike Johnson, the
speaker of the House of Representatives,
did not want
his own Republican party to vote on a an
issue on a motion that was brought up in
the House of Representatives Committee
on Rules, which decides what bills go to
the floor for a vote and what bills
don't.
a bill to demand the release of all this
information. That's counterintuitive,
right? The president said he wanted all
the information released. Uh the FBI
wants the information released. Pam
Bondi says that she wants the
information released. The American
people want the information released.
And then Mike Johnson says, "Oh my god,
we can't allow a vote to release the
information."
The Democrats are the ones who sponsored
this bill. This would give the Democrats
a kind of a cheap political victory. And
the likes of Thomas Massie and Marjorie
Taylor Green and a bunch of members of
the House Freedom Caucus were joining
with Democrats to vote yes to force a
release of the information. So what did
Mike Johnson do? He shut down the House
of Representatives and sent everybody
home
until September.
So, not only is there not going to be a
vote to force the release of this
information, there's not going to be a
vote on anything of any kind. Literally,
nothing will happen on Capitol Hill
because there is nobody on Capitol Hill.
They've all gone home. This is a
travesty, but it's something that we're
going to watch and we're going to keep
on. And please tune in on August 2nd. We
are going to interview somebody who
knows more about Jeffrey Epstein and
these details than anybody else in
America. We're going to lay all of that
out for you. In the meantime, again,
please do me that favor. Hit subscribe
and like. Please share it. Tell your
friends. Remember, it's free to
subscribe. It doesn't cost anybody
anything. But my goodness, it sure helps
us. I promised you that I'd uh at least
answer one question. And next week,
we're going to do an entire um uh
session here where I'll I'll answer
these these really wellthoughtout uh
well-considered questions. You deserve
an answer. You're going to get an
answer. But LJ 1066 poses a question
here that made me laugh out loud when I
thought of it because it's a good a good
question. LJ 1066 asks, "Is your show
going to discuss what's going on with
Xiinping?" of course the the premier of
China. I would love to know your
perspective on what him being missing
for weeks means. I'm going to answer
that with one of my anecdotes from the
CIA. I worked for a station chief
overseas who before he came to the CIA
worked in the State Department's uh
Bureau of Diplomatic Security.
And in 1976, he went with Henry
Kissinger to China to see Mount Maung.
And he and Kissinger arrived in China.
And virtually the moment they got off
the plane, Kissinger told the Chinese,
"I need to see Mao. I need to see Mao. I
need to see Ma." And they kept saying,
"Yes, yes, you will see Mao. He's
looking forward to seeing you, but first
we want you to see this guy, and then we
want you to see this guy, and then we're
going to have a dinner, and then we're
going to give you a tour of this
building, and then you're going to drive
around and, you know, look at the shops
or whatever. The whole time they were
there, Kissinger kept saying, "I have to
see Mao. I have to see Mao." Finally,
just before they're going to leave to go
to the airport, the Chinese tell
Kissinger, Mao is ready to see you. My
friend told me that they they walked
them into a room, an empty room that had
a wall of drapes all across one wall.
They opened the drapes and there was
Mao, but he was in bed. And the Chinese
host said, "Mao is sleeping and he can't
speak to you." And my friend said that
he whispered to Henry Kissinger, "He's
dead, isn't he?"
And Kissinger whispered back, "Don't
tell anybody."
It was another month before the Chinese
finally announced that Mao had died.
Well, Kissinger had to go back to
President Ford and say, "Mao's dead. We
saw him in the bed. He was clearly
dead." Now, L LJ 1066, to answer your
question, I'm not saying Xiinping is
dead, of course, but I think that when
Chinese leaders just go missing for
weeks at a time, it's because of a
health issue. He's an old man. We know
that he has had other health issues,
especially um uh congestive heart
failure. And I'm wondering if something
happened. he had a heart attack or he
had a stroke or something. I'm wondering
if we're going to finally get this
announcement that oh Xiinping decided to
retire
two months ago. They just never said
anything or oh my goodness, Xihinping's
dead. Uh just now it's just that he's
been out of commission. Who knows? You
know, world leaders are are weird. Or
maybe I should say the people around
world leaders are weird when it comes to
health issues. They always have been.
Um, I would put money though on the fact
that Xihinping is sick. Ladies and
gentlemen, I read all the comments. I
love the comments. Thank you for your
kindness in the comments, too. You've
said a lot of really nice things about
me and it really makes me want to keep
doing this a lot. So, thank you. And if
you have a question, please feel free to
leave it in the comments. We'll pull it
out and we'll do more of these sessions
where we can uh have Q&A and and get a
little deeper into some of these issues.
So, thanks for taking the time. I'm
looking forward to more of these and
we'll come back with more answers next
week.